MOHAMMAD ZAHID CCIEX2 (RS,SP)

http://www.zahid-stanikzai.com http://www.visualcv.com/stanikzai http://www.mzstanikzai.com

SUMMARY

My Name is Mohammad Zahid and I have 8+ years of practical experience in IT and Networking/Security in different industries. i.e. Banking, MicroFinance, Private Owned Companies, Government and Telecommunications. Currently I am holding Dual CCIE Certification from Cisco in Routing and Switching and Service Provider.

I am pursuing my CISSP Certification from ISC2 in Security. And I am Bachelor in Information Technology from ISBM. I have worked in different skills and position in the entire companies, which I was working and was involved in different projects, which were either mid-sized or big projects of IT and eGovernment. I have experience in eGov platform and all projects that had a big vision and high budget projects.

I have the ability to manage the team up to 50 employees which I have experienced in Telecommunication industries where I was last working as a Manager IP Core and Security.

EXPERIENCE

AFGHAN WIRELESS

Senior Manager - IP Operations

• Development and standardization of the IP Operations Department as per the SOP and standard approach. • Planning for migration and integrations of network appliances • Integration plan for the Cisco and Huawei Products, which are inclusive of the Planning, Preparing and Optimization Cycle. • 3G and LTE Network optimization, planning, implementation and overview of the new technologies. • Super Wifi Project implementation and management • Prepare and plan for the standardization of the Data Center according to TIA-942 Standards • Provide the Plan for the BGP implementation with the Core/Uplink ISPs. • Implementation of the MPLS/MP-BGP Plan • Managing the plan and procedure of the network migration and potential fallbacks with the Sub-ISPs • Organize and plan for the new technology plans • Preparation of the Budget for the IP Operations team, which should be inclusive of the current and future expand migration plan. • Ensure information is properly protected by assisting the Infrastructure team in developing secure architectures within Production & corporate network environment • Planning and Implementation of the Disaster Recovery Site for the IP OPS Nodes.

APPHOLIK 04 / 2015 - Present

Solutions Architect

- Mobile Application development architectural design
- iOS and Android integration planning
- System integration with Mobile Apps
- **Network Migration for Projects**
- System Integration and-System Management
- Assist and plan developers team on planning, designing and developing iOS and Android Apps
- Planning security implementation for all AppStore Apps of the company
- PalAlto appliances designing and implementation to the network
- Integration of mobile Apps with different vendors

AFGHAN WIRELESS

04 / 2014 - 04 / 2015

11 / 2015 - Present

Manager IP Core & Security

· Development and standardization of the Backbone Department as per the standard operation procedures. · Preparation and Planning of Routing Protocols Migration • Integration plan for the Cisco and Huawei Products, which are inclusive of the Planning, Preparing and Optimization Cycle. • 3G and LTE Network optimization, planning, implementation and overview of the new technologies. • Develop and plan the 3G migration/integration with the current 2G and GPRS network. • Provide a plan for the MSC/BSC Migration with the 3G nodes where it involves with the IP team • Prepare and plan for the standardization of the Data Center according to TIA-942 Standards • Provide the Plan for the BGP implementation with the Core/Uplink ISPs. • Implementation of the MPLS/MP-BGP Plan for the Current 2G-GPRS and 3G network on Cisco and Huawei Platforms. • Managing the plan and procedure of the network migration and potential fallbacks with the Sub-ISPs • Organize and plan for the new technology plans • Preparation of the Budget for the IP Backbone team, which should be inclusive of the current and future expand migration plan. • Ensure information is properly protected by assisting the Infrastructure team in developing secure architectures within Production & corporate network environment • Planning and Implementation of the Disaster Recovery Site for the IP BB Nodes.

GTR (GRAND TECHNOLOGY RESOURCES)

01/2012 - 04/2014

Senior Network Engineer

· Provide network design services which meet and exceed the needs of major financial services firm, ensuring adherence to departmental policies and procedures • Co-ordinate and define network requirements (i.e. design, configure, install, etc.) to include coordinating with other groups within and outside the Infrastructure team to determine the scope and objectives of proposed networking configurations • Oversee the timely and accurate analysis of company and third-party vendor requirements • Evaluating if network configuration is possible with existing resources and managing end user expectations to keep them at a realistic level • Develop and implement network backup and recovery plans to maintain reliable network operating system • Develop detailed implementation plans to accommodate network growth, security, and enhancements by maximizing functionality of network equipment (i.e. Cisco routers, gateways, switches, etc.) • Monitor network implementation, providing support in an timely and accurate manner • Analyze data traffic patterns within network infrastructure • Detecting operational problems and recommending improvements to ensure optimal performance • Make recommendations to management on enhancements to network that will improve the quality and reliability of the networks performance • Provide recommendations of the most cost-effective solution to management, including all cost, procedural, and contractual considerations necessary to make decisions • Research and identify new technologies available that offer business advancements • Ensure information is properly protected by assisting the Infrastructure team in developing secure architectures within Production & corporate network environment • Assist in devising disaster recovery operations/ procedures. • Assist bidding committee in preparation of technical specifications of any potential bids. • Assist Project Managers in designing technical specifications, integration plans & other areas where required

• Install Configure and Maintenance of all the servers including Domain Server, File Server, and Print Server. • Install, configure and maintenance of CISCO switches including Catalyst 3750, 3560, 3550, 2960 and CISCO routers 2811, 1841, 2522, 2511, 2500, Frame Relay Switch, 7206. • Create an INTRANET solution for OXUS branches and main office located all over country. • Manage all components of project internal and external IT networks, including but not limited to design, deployment, testing, installation and configuration of project network and workstations. • Create Physical and logical network diagrams, bills of quantities, scheduling projections, inventory reports, site survey reports, and other documents as required. Prepare periodic progress reports as requested by the supervisor. • Established IT policies and procedures in accordance with OXUS regulations and guidelines, including practical OCTOPUS(Bank Database) database manuals for the front office and back office users. • Established a recovery Data solution of data loss or data corruption. Managed, organized and conducted OCTOPUS trainings for basic and super users in branches and departments heads. Ensured that OXUS needs in terms of IT equipment, procedures and training were met on a timely. • Led the overall IT operation ensuring that all OXUS units received quality, adequate and timely IT support and services in terms of networking, connectivity, databases and computer troubleshooting. • Planned, monitored, and appraised the department staff performance. Installed, configured and maintained WSUS Server, Cisco ASA 5520 firewall and VPN. • Installed and configured PRTG and firewall analyzer for bandwidth and network monitoring. • Established a proper Disaster recovery system. A strong backup strategy implemented for maintaining offsite and onsite backups. • Uses combinations of strong technology skills and business acumen to provide analysis, definition and direction to IT-related development.

AFGHAN UNITED BANK 06 / 2008 - 11 / 2010

IT Officer

• Overseeing and Managing Widows 2008/2003 servers, including DHCP, DNS, WINS, Active Directory • Train office users on databases. • Manage, troubleshoot and oversee of Lotus Notes domino server (Lotus Notes Exchange server). • Manage, troubleshoot and oversee of all servers and Server application maintenance such as Kaspersky Antivirus server administration kit (centralized protection), Windows server 2003 and windows server 2008 maintenance LAN and WAN connectivity and WSUS. • Work closely with Procurement, Logistics and Finance to update inventory of IT equipment • Support and maintenance of core banking system (FlexCube), information systems and the availability of communication. • Assesses countywide networking needs; researches, recommends, and develops criteria and test plans for evaluation; coordinates the testing and installation of new networking technologies, equipment, and services. • Monitor and evaluate security programs; develop and implement IT- and function-specific contingency and disaster recovery plans. • Establishing data integrity and security policies and procedures for user accounts, data creation, data manipulation and data storage. • Recommends hardware and system configuration changes to optimize database and systems performance. • Participate in the development and implementation of department goals, objectives, policies and priorities for assigned programs.

TRAMCO GROUP OF COMPANIES

08 / 2005 - 06 / 2008

IT Officer

• Installing and configuring computer hardware operating systems and applications • Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks • Talking staff/clients through a series of actions, either face to face or over the telephone to help set up systems or resolve issues • Troubleshooting system and network problems and diagnosing and solving hardware/software faults • Replacing parts as required • Supporting the roll-out of new applications • Setting up new users' accounts and profiles and dealing with password issues • Responding within agreed time limits to call-outs • Working continuously on a task until completion (or referral to third parties, if appropriate) • Prioritizing and managing many open cases at one time • Rapidly establishing a good working relationship with customers and other professionals, e.g., software developers • Testing and evaluating new technology • Conducting electrical safety checks on computer equipment

EDUCATION

INDIAN SCHOOL OF BUSINESS MANAGEMENT	2013 - 2015
Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) , IT Management	
AXWAY	2013 - 2013
Axway Certified Associate , Online Certificate Status Protocol (OCSP)	
ENTRUST	2013 - 2013
Entrust Certified , Public Key Infrastructure (PKI)	
THALES	2013 - 2013
nShield Cerified System Engineer (nCSE) , Hardware Security Module (HSM)	
INDIAN SCHOOL OF BUSINESS & MANAGEMENT (ISBM)	2010 - 2013
Bachelor's degree , IT Management	
NETSCOPE	2012 - 2012
CCIE Bootcamp , CCIE R&S LAB	
Basic Switching, IGPs (RIP, OSPF, EIGRP), BGP, MPLS, Security, Advance Switching, QoS, MPLS	
CISCO	2008 - 2012

CCNA, CCNP, CCIE R&S Written, CCIE R&S Lab , Routing & Switching | Networking

MICROSOFT MCP, MCSA, MCSE, MCTS, MCITP (Enterprise Admin), MS Servers	2006 - 2009
NADERIA HIGH SCHOOL Diploma , High School Subjects	2003 - 2005
High School Student	

INTERESTS

Complex Cisco Labs, Technology Research

CERTIFICATIONS

CCIE SPV3 LAB Cisco · License: 40010	10 / 2014
CCIE SP V3 WRITTEN Cisco · License: 40010	06/2014
CCIE R&S V4 CISCO · License: 40010	07/2013
AXWAY CERTIFIED ASSOCIATE Axway · License: ICN 101024	06 / 2013
CCIE R&S WRITTEN CISCO · License: CSCO11943501	06 / 2012
CCNP R&S CISCO · License: CSCO11943501	12/2011
CCNA R&S CISCO · License: CSCO11943501	04/2011
MCITP (ENTERPRISE EDITION) Microsoft · License: 7857230	06 / 2009
MCTS Microsoft · License: 7857230	03 / 2009
MCSE 2003 Microsoft · License: 7857230	12/2008
MCSA MCSA (MESSAGING) Mircosoft · License: 7857230	11 / 2008
MCP Microsoft · License: 7857230	10 / 2008

LANGUAGES

- Pashto (Native or bilingual proficiency)
- Dari
- Urdu
- English

PUBLICATIONS

ZAHID-STANIKZAI.COM 08 / 2013

 $Internet ~\cdot~ Authors: \textit{Mohammad Zahid CCIEx2 (RS,SP)} ~\cdot~ \underline{\textit{http://www.zahid-stanikzai.com}}$

I have created this site for my friends, family and/or anyone who wants to know more about me, and follow what i am learning, It contains content of a personal nature rather than on behalf of any company. Thoughts and words are all mine and if you think that you can do it better, please go ahead and do it:)